A Guide to the Seward Forest Papers, 1900-1989 (bulk 1920-1925)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Seward Forest Papers 1900-1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10026, 10026-a
This collection consists of ca. 17,600 items (ca. 21 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Series I, II, IV, archival transfer Mr. [Guy] Estes, November 29, 1974, Seward Forest, Triplet, Virginia. Series III, archival transfer B.F.D. Runk, June 18, 1975, 160-D, Gilmer Hall.
Biographical/Historical Information
John B. Lewis, naturalist, b. Illinois, October 9, 1868, d. June 8, 1957. Naturalist in residence at Seward Forest, 1940-1945. Prior to work at Seward Forest, served as county agricultural extension agent in Norfolk, Amelia, and Brunswick Counties, Virginia. Author of numerous articles on nature in science journals and Virginia newspapers, including the Southside Virginia News (Petersburg) and the Richmond News- Leader.
Walter Merritt Seward, b. September 22, 1860, d. December 20, 1932. Son of [Robert] Merritt Seward and Susan Everett Branch (b. May 20, 1840, d. Aug. 15, 1928), who after her first husband's death married John H. Dunn. Seward was an 1886 graduate of University of Virginia School of Medicine. Practiced in New York City until 1912 then returned to Brunswick County. Bequeathed entire estate to the University of Virginia, including ca. 3,600 acres of land in Brunswick and Greensville Counties, Virginia, for instructional use in forestry.
Alfred Akerman, b. Bartow County, Georgia, July 3, 1876, d. Sept. 20, 1962. One of eight sons of Amos T. Akerman, US Attorney General during the administration of Ulysses S. Grant. Forester and first director of University of Virginia Seward Forest (1935-1950). Earned Master's Degree in Forestry at Yale in 1902 where he taught until 1904; served as State Forester of Massachusetts, 1904-1906. Professor of Forestry at University of Georgia where he held the Chair of Forestry in a position endowed by philanthropist George Foster Peabody. Served in the Virginia Forest Service as District Forester for Southeastern Virginia, 1921- 1926. Associate professor of forestry at the University of Virginia beginning in 1928; in 1935, the first year of active development of the Seward Forest, became the Forest director, a position in which he served until 1950 when Guy Estes succeeded him. During retirement continued to live in Brunswick County, Virginia, working part-time on a consulting basis at Seward Forest.
Scope and Content
The Seward Forest papers consist of ca. 17,600 items (50 Hollingers, ca. 21 linear feet), 1833-1974, concerning the founding and operations of the University of Virginia's Seward Experimental Forest (or Seward Forest), a tract of 3,600 acres of land located near Triplet (sometimes or previously spelled Triplett), Virginia, in Brunswick County with part in Greensville County, Virginia. The property was willed to the University of Virginia by Walter Merritt Seward, an 1886 University of Virginia School of Medicine graduate to be used, as stipulated in Seward's will, as "an instrumentality for instruction in the science of forestry, and in the art of cutting, sawing, manufacturing and marketing the products of the forest, and at the same time to aid the University of Virginia in the development of its School of Forestry and to further the usefulness of said institution." The University of Virginia operated Seward Forest from 1935 to 1974, sawing at its mill timber supplied by local woodcutters and selling wood products such as lumber and firewood. It also served as an experimental research facility for studying forestry practices and was used by personnel from the University of Virginia and elsewhere for this purpose.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in the following series: I. Papers of Seward/Dunn Families. II. Papers of John B. Lewis III. Papers of Alfred Akerman. IV. Papers of the Seward Forest. Within series papers are generally arranged alphabetically and chronologically for correspondence and alphabetically by topic for all other materials.
Series I, Papers of Seward and Dunn Families, includes papers from Walter Seward's stepfather, John H. Dunn, and Seward's father, [Robert] Merritt Seward, as well as materials generated by Walter Seward himself. Dunn's papers include an 1842 tax receipt which lists "tax on negroes" at 40 cents each, correspondence, and financial records. Seward's materials include much correspondence with his mother, Susan Everett Dunn (nee Branch), financial records, notes concerning his medical practice, notes from a class on general chemistry given by J.W. Mallet at the University of Virginia in 1885-1886, and an 1888 patient ledger.
Series II, Papers of John B. Lewis, are the papers of John Lewis, for six years in the 1940s naturalist in residence at Seward Forest. Lewis's papers contain correspondence with laymen, scientists, and government officials, checklists on flora and fauna (birds, mammals, and reptiles and amphibians) observed and collected in Kentucky and Virginia, work books, and a card index of plants. Some of Lewis's bird observations in the collection date from the late 19th and early 20th Centuries. Manuscript and copies of newspaper columns on nature topics written by Lewis for Virginia newspapers are also included.
Series III, Papers of Alfred Akerman, are the papers of the first director of the Seward Forest (1935-1950) and contain material on his pre-Seward Forest career as well as on his activities at the Forest. Akerman's career paralleled the development of forestry in the United States, and his papers in Series III offer insight on the field's evolution. The collection includes his correspondence from the first half of the 20th Century with philanthropist George Foster Peabody and C.A. Schenck of the Biltmore Forest School. There is material covering his career as professor of forestry at the University of Georgia, 1906-1914, including letters to and from University of Georgia Chancellor David C. Barrow and class materials, examinations, and notes on students, Akerman's employment with the Virginia Forest Service from 1921-1926 is well documented in the collection which covers such topics as forest management, warden appointments, and fire protection. Correspondence with one of his brothers, Clement, a professor at Hood College in Oregon, covers fiscal and political topics and includes several papers and reports written by Clement. Copies of reports and pamphlets written by Akerman, including Forests of Surry County Virginia, and The White Cedar of the Dismal Swamp, as well as the notes used in preparing them, form part of the collection. Akerman wrote and saved numerous newspaper articles and letters to the editor, and these are preserved in the collection. Many of the articles, on politics and world affairs, as well as natural science, include his commentary. Akerman's career at the University of Virginia, starting in 1928 as an associate professor of forestry, is documented in the collection by classroom notes and examinations, correspondence with University administration, and material on the founding of Seward Forest in the first half of the 1930s following Walter Seward's death. Akerman was a friend of Walter Seward, and throughout his lifetime wrote often about Seward's life. Included in papers prepared by Akerman on the life of Walter Seward is a copy of Seward's will bequeathing his estate to the University of Virginia. Series III also has a number of unidentified photographs of member of the Akerman and Scudder families.
Series IV, Papers of the Seward Forest, contain chronological files concerning the daily operation of the Forest, with information on Seward Forest personnel, lumber sales and sawmill operations, local and state retail and service businesses (i.e., hardware stores, timber companies, and automobile repairs), payroll and motor vehicle records, and correspondence with University of Virginia administrators, other academic institutions, and county and state government officials. Alfred Akerman and Guy Estes, first and second directors of the Seward Forest, are principal correspondents. Depression-era correspondence contains requests from individuals seeking employment at the Seward Forest. Much of the correspondence from the World War II era concerns Akerman's dealings with rationing, personnel staffing problems due to the draft, and wartime government regulations affecting the operation of the Forest. Postwar correspondence shows an increasing amount of paperwork dealing with University of Virginia and Virginia state regulations and official policies and their effects on Seward Forest operations. Series IV also contains numerous topical file folders including annual reports and budget data, records on tree plantations on the grounds of the University of Virginia in Charlottesville, and correspondence of Forest work crew members. One individual on the crew was Ervin H. Wright, from Gasburg, Virginia, whose 1942-1944 correspondence indicates he was with Company A, 116th Infantry Regiment, 29th Infantry Division. According to a 1947 newspaper article, Wright was killed in action in Normandy on D-Day, June 6, 1944. There are several letters and postcards written between Alfred Akerman and Wright. Forest scenes and personnel are featured in a collection of photographs of the Forest. There are also files on Seward Forest infrastructure and utilities (roads, bridges, electricity, water supply, etc.). Numerous bound volumes (notebooks, ledgers, etc.) prepared by Akerman and others prior to the founding of the Seward Forest as well as records kept during Forest operations cover such topics as land surveys, sawmill operations, personnel records, and finances.
Contents List
- Series I: Papers of Seward and Dunn Families
  - John H. Dunn Papers 1833-1843, 1874 (Box 1)
  - Robert M. Seward Papers 1857-1860 (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Papers 1877-1895 (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Doctor of Medicine Diploma, University of Virginia 1886 (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Papers 1896-1904 (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Papers 1905-1906 (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Papers 1907-1910 (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Papers 1911-1932 (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Papers n.d. (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Papers: Notes on Course Given by Chemist J.W. Mallet 1885-1886 (Box 1)
  - Walter M. Seward Papers: Patient Leger 1888 (Box 2)
- Series II: Papers of John B. Lewis
  - Biological Survey/Fish and Wildlife Service 1935, 1937-1944, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Birds: Audobon Society Membership Certificates 1886 (Box 2)
  - Birds 1882-1944 (Box 2)
  - Birds: Birds of New York n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Alfred Akerman 1940, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: M.L. Fernald 1938-1940, 1942-1946 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, A-F 1928-1947 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, G-K 1928-1948 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, L-P 1882, 1924-1946 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous, Q-Z 1918, 1924, 1930-1944 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Newspaper Columns 1935-1939 (Box 3)
  - Mammals 1937-1943 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Columns: Miscellaneous Fragments n.d. (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Columns: Nature 1928-1930, 1937-1941, 1944-1946 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Columns 1890, 1938-1942, 1944 (Box 3)
    Typescript
  - Newspaper Columns/Indexes: Richmond News-Leader 1930-1935 (Box 4)
    8 folders
  - Newspaper Columns/Indexes: Richmond News-Leader 1935-1939 (Box 5)
    6 folders
  - Notebook (Untitled): [Nature Observations, Mainly Birds] 1922-1943 (Box 6)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box 6)
  - Plants: Amelia County, Virginia 1834, 1936-1940 (Box 6)
  - Plants: Annotated List of Plants Collected in Seward Forest in 1940 1940 (Box 6)
  - Plants: Annotated Lists of Plants Collected in Seward Forest (Some Lists Included Greensville and Southampton Counties and Adjoining Territories) 1942-1945 (Box 6)
  - Plants: Catalogs of Plants Collected in Seward Forest and Adjacent Territory 1940-1944 (Box 6)
  - Plants: A Checklist of Plants in the Washington-Baltimore Area by Frederick J. Herrmann 1941 (Box 6)
  - Plants: Claytonia [Newsletter] Published by the Committee on State Flora, of the Virginia Academy of Science 1934-1936 (Box 7)
  - Plants: Committee on the Flora of Richmond and Vicinity, Meeting Minutes, July 15, 1932 1932 (Box 7)
  - Plants: Committee on Virginia Flora Reports 1939, 1941, 1943-1944 (Box 7)
  - Plants: Lists of the Woody Plants of Southeastern Brunswick County n.d. (Box 7)
  - Reports by John B. Lewis as Amelia County Extension Agent and on Work Done in Seward Forest 1933, 1937, 1940-1945 (Box 7)
  - Reptiles and Amphibians n.d., ca. 1938-1959 (Box 7)
  - Engagements (Speaking Notes) by John B. Lewis n.d., 1937, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Taxonomy Notes n.d. (Box 7)
  - Virginia Wildlife Federation Correspondence, Memoranda, etc. 1936-1937 (Box 7)
- Series III: Papers of Alfred Akerman
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence 1902-1907 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1908 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1909-1910 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1911-1912 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1913-1915 (Box 8)
    - Topographic Maps and Property Surveys of the Champion Lumber Co., Sunburst, North Carolina, the Azalea Woodworking Co., Azalea, North Carolina, and Sawmill Owned by W.I. Stovall, near Sautee, Georgia n.d., 1913, 9 items (Box 8)
    - Correspondence 1922 Jan-Sep (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1922 Oct-Dec (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1923 Jan-Feb (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1923 Mar-Jul (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1923 Aug-Sep (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1923 Oct (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1923 Nov-Dec (Box 9)
    - Correspondence 1924 Jan-Feb (Box 10)
    - Correspondence 1924 Mar-Apr (Box 10)
    - Correspondence 1924 May-Jun (Box 10)
    - Correspondence 1924 Jul-Nov (Box 10)
    - Correspondence 1925 Jan-Apr (Box 10)
    - Correspondence 1925 May-Jun (Box 10)
    - Correspondence 1925 Jul-Dec (Box 10)
    - Correspondence 1926-1931 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1932-1935 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence 1938-1958 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence - Clement Akerman (includes 4 reports by Clement Akerman) 1930-1934 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence - David C. Barrow 1906-1912 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence - L.A. Berckmanns 1908-1909, 1912 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - The Berry School 1908, 1913 (Box 12)
    - Blueprint Development Plan of the Berry School, Blueprint 7-1/2 in./mile Map of Eastern Georgia 1908-1909 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - The Biltmore Forest School (C.A. Schenck, C.D. Howe) 1907-1912 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - Allen Chamberlain 1906-1908, 1911-19122 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - F.B. Knapp (Eric Forest School) 1907-1908, 1910-1912 (Box 12)
    - Eric/F.B. Knapp Outlook System Topographic Maap ca. 1908 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - Louis B. Magid 1907-1908, 1913 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - George Foster Peabody 1905-1908, 1911-1913, 1924, 1935 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - A.B. Recknagel 1907-1908 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - C.S. Sargent 1907, 1909, 1911 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - Walter M. Seward 1923-1924, 1928-1932 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - University of Georgia Board of Trustees 1907-1908 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence - University of Virginia Administration 1928, 1932-1934, 1941, 1948-1949, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Topical Files
    - Alfred Akerman - Biography and Genealogy (Akerman and Scudder Families) 1901-1960 (Box 12)
    - Alfred Akerman - Catalog of Library Books 1962-1964 (Box 12)
    - Alfred Akerman - Diary (Typescript) 1921 Sep-1923 Jul (Box 12)
    - Alfred Akerman - Miscellaneous Materials from Period in New England (includes notes on lecture by Gifford Pinchot) 1901-1905 (Box 12)
    - Alfred Akerman - Tombstone Purchase 1963 (Box 12)
    - Black Walnut Trees n.d., 1907-1942, 1969 (Box 13)
    - Biltmore Forest School Newsletter 1909-1914, 1930 (Box 13)
    - The Chosen Tree Method of Thinning, Harvesting, and Reproducing Stands of Timber (report by and research materials of Alfred Akerman) 1937-1949, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Cooperative Extension Work in Agriculture and Home Economics (VPI, Virginia Forest Service, and US Department of Agriculture newsletter) 1932-1935 (Box 13)
    - The Criminal Fee (manuscript of a fictional story by Alfred Akerman) n.d. (Box 13)
    - Foreign Debts of the United States Government (paper by Clement Akerman) 1925 (Box 13)
    - Jefferson Fund for Forest Research n.d., 1929-1934 (Box 14)
    - Lake and Forest (incomplete copy of book) n.d. (Box 14)
    - National Conservation Commission/Congress 1908, 1913 (Box 14)
    - National Forest Policy n.d. (Box 14)
    - National Forest Policy n.d. (Box 14)
    - Map of Natural Forest Regions of South America 1911 (Box 14)
    - National Forest Policy (with Courtland S. Winn) 1916-1929 (Box 14)
    - National Forest Policy by State (with Courtland S. Winn) - Alabama-Maryland 1916 (Box 14)
    - National Forest Policy by State (with Courtland S. Winn) - Michigan-Wyoming 1916 (Box 14)
    - Newspaper Articles, Letters to the Editor, etc., by or about Alfred Akerman n.d., 1913-1939 (Box 14)
    - Newspaper Clipping n.d. (Box 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1905-1919 (Box 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1920-1929 (Box 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1930-1939 (Box 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1940-1960 (Box 15)
    - Newpaper Clippings with Commentary by Alfred Akerman 1907-1945 (Box 15)
    - Notes, Drawings and Miscellaneous Materials n.d., 1907-1929 (Box 15)
    - Photographs (Alfred Akerman, Akerman/Scudder Families) n.d., 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Pine Trees (Loblolly, Longleaf, Slash) 1916-1952 (Box 15)
    - Report on the Examination of Lands of the Camp Manufacturing Company (report by and research material of Alfred Akerman) 1924-1926, 1929 (Box 16)
    - Reports and Studies on Forestry and Miscellaneous Topics by Alfred Akerman n.d. (Box 16)
    - Reports and Studies on Forestry and Miscellaneous Topics by Alfred Akerman 1908-1956 (Box 16)
    - Reports and Studies on Forestry and Miscellaneous Topics by Others n.d. (Box 16)
    - Reports and Studies on Forestry and Miscellaneous Topics by Others 1904-1916 (Box 16)
    - Reports and Studies on Forestry and Miscellaneous Topics by Others 1921-1943 (Box 16)
    - Seed Tree Law n.d., 1942 (Box 16)
    - Seed Tree Law 1943 (Box 17)
    - Seed Tree Law 1944-1949 (Box 17)
    - Seed Tree Law 1950-1959 (Box 17)
    - Life of Walter M. Seward 1927-1965 (Box 17)
    - Life of Robert Sharp 1880, 1955-1962 (Box 17)
    - Silvicultue and Practical Forestry Course at Amherst 1902-1912 (Box 17)
    - Forests of Surry County, Virginia (report by and research material of Alfred Akerman) 1924-925, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Surveying Lecture Notes, Syracuse, New York 1918 (Box 18)
    - Tax Delinquent Land Policy 1932-1933 (Box 18)
    - Taxation Policy (emphasis on Georgia) n.d., 1908, 1921, 1924, 1929-1936 (Box 18)
    - Thinning (includes Georgia State Board of Forestry Report, Forest Thinning, by Alfred Akerman) n.d., 1894, 1912, 1923-1943 (Box 18)
    - Graphs and Miscellaneous Papers on Thinning 1938, 1943, 7 items (Box 18)
    - University of Georgia School of Forestry - Annual Reports 1907-1914 (Box 18)
    - University of Georgia School of Forestry - Class Schedules, Grades, Students n.d. (Box 18)
    - University of Georgia School of Forestry - Examinations, Scores, Tests 1908-1914 (Box 18)
    - University of Georgia School of Forestry - Reports by Students n.d., 1912-1914 (Box 18)
    - University of Georgia School of Forestry - Summer Forest Camp 1909-1910 (Box 18)
    - University of Virginia - Forestry Examinations, Lecture Notes, Correspondence 1928-1932 (Box 19)
    - University of Virginia - Forestry Examinations, Lecture Note, Correspondence 1933-1937 (Box 19)
    - University of Virginia - Founding of Seward Experimental Forest 1927-1938 (Box 19)
    - Utilization 1902, 1915-1934 (Box 19)
    - The White Cedar of the Dismal Swamp (report by and research material of Alfred Akerman) n.d., 1908-1935 (Box 19)
- Series IV: Papers of the Seward Forest
  - Subseries A: Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Correspondence, A-Z 1933 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, A-Z 1934 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, A-E 1935 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, F-L 1935 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, M-R 1935 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, S-Z 1935 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, A-E 1936 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, F-L 1936 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, M-R 1936 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, S-Z 1936 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, A-C 1937 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, D-L 1937 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, D-L 1937 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, M-R 1937 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, S-Z 1937 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, A-C 1938 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, D-L 1938 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, M-N 1938 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, O-P 1938 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, Q-Z 1938 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1939 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, C 1939 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, D-L 1939 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, M-O 1939 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, P-Z 1939 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1940 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, C-D 1940 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, E-H 1940 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, I-O 1940 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, P 1940 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, Q-S 1940 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, Q-S 1940 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1940 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1941 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, C 1941 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, D-G 1941 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, H 1941 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, I-N 1941 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, O-R 1941 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, S 1941 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1941 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1942 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, C-D 1942 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, E-F 192 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, G-H 1942 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, I-N 1942 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, O-R 1942 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, S 1942 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1942 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, A-C 1943 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, D-G 1943 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, H-L 1943 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, M-N 1943 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, O-P 1943 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, Q-Z 1943 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1944 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, C-E 1944 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, F-K 1944 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, L-M 1944 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, N-R 1944 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, S 1944 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1944 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1945 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, C-E 1945 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, F-L 1945 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, M-N 1945 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, O-R 1945 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, Q-Z 1945 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1946 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, C-E 1946 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, F-L 1946 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, M-Q 1946 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, R-S 1946 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1946 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1947 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, C-D 1947 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, E-H 1947 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, I-L 1947 (Box 31)
    - Correspondece, M-O 1947 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, P-S 1947 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1947 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1948 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, C-F 1948 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, G-L 1948 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, M-Q 1948 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, R-S 1948 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, T-Z 1948 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, A-B 1949 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, C-G 1949 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, H-K 1949 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, L-O 1949 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, P 1949 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, Q-S 1949 (Box 33)